In this module we've talked about
这个模块中我们已经讨论了
a document retrieval task and we've also talked about a notion of clustering where
一个文件检索的任务 还讨论了一个聚类的概念
we're trying to uncover some underlying structure in the data and we talked
用来揭示数据的潜在结构 我们
about many different areas in which this notion of clustering can be really useful.
还谈到了一些聚类这个概念有用武之地的领域
So let's go through the workflow for a clustering algorithm.
现在让我们来从头讨论一下一个聚类算法的工作流程
And if you feel like you already know this at this point because you've seen this
如果你觉得你觉得你已经对此了然于胸了 因为你已经
workflow now in two other modules.
在另外两个模块中见过这个流程图了
Well, wake up!
那么 赶快醒一醒
Because this one's going to be a bit different.
因为这次这个可是有点不太一样的
Okay, so let's talk about our training data.
好的 让我们来看看我们的训练数据
Here, our training data for
在这里 我们的训练数据是
a document clustering task is going to be a document ID and
用来进行文件聚类的文件代号和
document text table.
文本表
So we have a whole bunch of documents.
所以我们有一堆文件
And we have all the texts associated with each of those.
以及与它们对应的文本
And then we're gonna extract some set of features.
然后我们将会提取一些特征量
And we talked about a lot of different ways to represent a document.
我们之前谈到过一些描绘一个文件的不同的方法
But the one that I'll use just as an example here is our tf-idf.
这里我要用到其中一个叫做"tf-idf"的方法
Term frequency-inverse document frequency representation.
全称叫做词频-逆文档频率法
And then what we're gonna do is we're gonna try and
我们下一步要做的是试着
cluster our documents based on this representation.
用这个表示法来对我们的文件进行聚类
So we're gonna put these features through some machine learning model.
所以我们将把这些特征量放入一些机器学习的模型中
Which in this case is a clustering model.
在这里我们用的是一个聚类模型
And we're gonna output for each document a cluster label.
对每个文件我们会输出一个聚类标签
So the output white hat is our cluster label.
那么这里的输出量y帽就是我们的聚类标签
Okay, so here's where things get interesting,
好的 有意思的是
because we wanna assess the accuracy of our cluster labels.
因为我们打算评估我们的聚类结果的准确度
Well, in this case we don't have true cluster labels, so
当然 这里我们并没有真正的集群标签 因此
I should say this is our predicted, or estimated, cluster label.
我还是把它称为我们的预测或者预估标签
But we don't have a true cluster label to compare against.
而我们并没有一个可以用来比对的真实标签
So this y here, it does not exist.
因此这里的y 它并不存在
And that's because, as we talked about, we're in an unsupervised learning setting.
这是因为 就像我们提到过的那样 我们的设定是无监督式学习
Unsupervised.
无监督式的
Okay.
好
So we don't have that but
所以我们没有真正的标签 但是
somehow we wanna assess some measure of accuracy of our clustering.
我们需要用某种方法来评估我们的聚类准确度
So let's draw a little picture here which is gonna be our Voronoi tessellation and
所以让我们在这里画一个小的图 也就是我们的沃罗诺伊图 还有
our k-means algorithm where we have some set of cluster centers and we have data.
我们的k均值算法以及集群中心的集合 我们还有数据
I should say our data look like this, I don't know,
我不知道 假设我们的数据长这样
I'm just gonna draw some points here.
我在这里画一下点
And the measure of accuracy that we're gonna use,
我们的准确度的度量方法
the way we're gonna measure our quality is to look at how coherent our clustering is.
也就是我们用来质量评估的是聚类的一致性
So we're gonna look at the distances from each observation to
我们会测量每个观测点到
their assigned cluster center.
它所在的集群中心的距离
And a good clustering algorithm has those distances very small.
一个好的聚类算法中这些距离会很小
Okay, so the goal is to minimize these distances and so what we see is to measure
所以我们的目标是最小化这些距离 而我们需要测量的是
this accuracy, to measure these distances, what we need is our data.
准确度 要测量这些距离 我们需要原始数据
We need our tf-idf vectors.
我们需要我们的词频-逆文档频率
So those are gonna come in here, and then we also need the cluster centers.
所以那些值会从这里输入 然后我们还需要集群中心
And so W hat, that's our current estimate of,
所以W帽 也就是我们的当前估计值
that's our model parameter here and the k means algorithm.
是我们的模型参量 而k均值算法
It's our cluster, whoops.
这是我们的集群 啊
Let's see if we can spell that correctly, cluster centers.
让我看看我们有没有评对这个词 集群中心
That's what W hat represents.
那是W帽的指代意义
And so of course to measure these distances we also need W hat.
当然我们也需要用W帽来测算距离
So instead of having actual cluster labels to assess accuracy we're
因此与其用真实的集群标签来评估准确度
gonna take our document representation and our cluster centers.
我们不如用文件标识和集群中心
Plug it into this quality measure,
把原始数据输入到质量度量中
which is looking at distances to cluster centers.
用于计算到集群中心的距离
That's our measure of error, though it's not really an error.
那是我们计算误差的度量 虽然它其实不是误差
It's just a measure of.
只是能估量
Oops.
啊哦
Just a measure of quality.
只是能估量质量
So I won't put that word there.
所以我就不把那个词写在那了
Okay, so I think that's a little confusing.
好了 我想这是有点乱
But let's just write distances to cluster centers.
但是就让我们标成到集群中心的距离
And then what's our algorithm?
那我们的算法是什么呢？
We're talking about k-means as a method of doing clustering.
我们之前谈到过k均值是一个聚类的方法
Of course there are others, but let's focus on k-means, well,
当然还有其他的方法 但是这里我们集中讨论k均值 那么
what's k-means doing?
k均值是怎么算的呢？
Let's just redraw this diagram, actually, I can just switch to another color.
让我们重新画一下这个图 好吧 干脆让我换一种颜色好了
That will save us some time here.
那样我们可以节约点时间
Well, k-means is trying to minimize this distance, or the sum of these distances,
好的 k均值是在试着最小化这个距离 或者说这些距离的总和
and the way it's doing that is iteratively it's updating so
最小化的方式是通过迭代循环
this was our W hat that we had before and we're moving it
所以这个是我们之前的W帽 我们把它更新成
to a new W hat that represents the center of mass of these points.
这个新的W帽 用来表示这些点的质量中心
So these points are getting shifted.
因此这些点会发生偏移
And this point will go directly on top of that observation
而这个点会直接放在这个观测量上
and so this is the work flow of clustering.
这就是这个聚类算法的工作流程
Let's just say it at a high level one more time.
让我们再从一个高水平上来总结一下
We take our documents, we represent them in some way, using either raw word counts,
我们拿到原始数据 用某种方法来表示它们 可以是单词统计量
tf-idf, normalizations of these things.
可以是词频-逆文档频率 或者这类数据的标准化值
Lots of different bigrams, trigrams, things we can look at for
我们可以用像二元或者三元词组来
our document representation.
表示我们的文件
Then our clustering algorithm, like k-means is producing clustering labels and
然后我们的聚类算法 比如k均值算法 可以输出集群标签
iteratively, we're looping through here again and again updating
并且我们可以通过迭代来一次次地更新
our cluster centers, that's the parameters of this clustering model.
集群中心 也就是这个聚类模型的参量
By looking at how far our assigned observations are to those cluster centers.
迭代更新的依据是观测量到集群中心的距离
So in this module in contrast to other modules we actually presented you with
不同于其他模块 在这个模块中 我们为大家
some of the algorithmic details behind the methods that we're looking at.
详细地讲解了一些算法的背后的细节
Specifically for clustering, we talked about the k-means algorithm, and then for
尤其是对聚类 我们讨论了k均值算法 以及
our document retrieval task, we also talked about doing nearest neighbor
文件检索问题 我们还谈到了相邻社区检索问题
search, and provided some of the algorithmic details for that, and
并提供了解决问题的算法的细节
you specifically explore that in an ipython notebook for
你还特别研究了用ipython Notebook
doing Wikipedia entry retrieval.
如何进行维基百科条目检索
So, at this point, you really should be able to go out there and
因此 到这里 你应该可以走出课堂
build a really cool retrieval system for doing news article retrieval.
搭建一个炫酷的新闻稿件的检索系统
Or any other really, really, really cool retrieval that I can't think of right now.
或者一个炫酷到我都想不到的其他检索系统
But of course there's lots of interesting examples.
当然还有好多好多有趣的例子
So go out there and think of ideas that I can't think of right now.
所以 同学们 请务必走向大千世界 多多探索新的好主意
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community